const e="crk",o=200,t=120,a=[{id:123,question:"What Josiah, the king of Judah, is best remembered for in Jewish history is ",option:{a:"His ability to destroy all the shine of Baals",b:"His order that the bones and tombs of the prophets of God must be preserved ",c:"His strong opposition to Pharaoh-Neco of Egypt ",d:"His reparation of the temples of God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:124,question:"After receiving an order from God, Jonah went down to…………….  ",option:{a:"Joppa ",b:"Tarshish  ",c:"Nineveh",d:"Jerusalem "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:125,question:"True religion, according to Amos’ submission, is the one in which  ",option:{a:"God is always appeased with sacrifices and tithes ",b:"Foods and drinks are served as a mark of love ",c:"Justice and righteousness flows like an endless stream  ",d:"Feast and solemn assemblies play important roles "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:126,question:"The last born of Gomer for Hoshea was ………….  ",option:{a:"Jezreel",b:"Loammi ",c:"Diblaim  ",d:"Loruhamah "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:127,question:"According to Paul in Romans, the law and the prophets bore witness to the righteousness of God but man could not be justified until he  ",option:{a:"Had faith in Jesus ",b:"Saw the glory of God ",c:"Made a serious personal effort ",d:"submitted wholly to the law "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:128,question:"One of the following was not among the religious sects in the New Testament ",option:{a:"The Pharisees",b:"The Nazarenes ",c:"The Essences   ",d:"The Sadducees"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:129,question:"One of the following  is not correct about the order of creation in the Creation Stories ",option:{a:"the evening came before the morning ",b:"darkness came before light",c:"animals were created before man ",d:"the morning came before the evening"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:130,question:"What was Cain’s immediate reaction to the acceptance of Abel’s offering?",option:{a:"He offered another sacrifice ",b:"He was angry and his countenance fell ",c:"He was angry with God",d:"He was angry with Abel "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:131,question:"Pick the odd out of the following characters:  ",option:{a:"Saul   ",b:"David",c:"Jonathan",d:"Solomon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:132,question:"“Talitha cumi”  means  ",option:{a:"Dorcas, Arise",b:"Little girl, I say to you, arise ",c:"Thy will be done",d:"Jesus is coming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:133,question:"Who according to James blaspheme the honourable name by which Christians are called",option:{a:"Non believers",b:"Pagan rulers",c:"Antichrists",d:"Rich people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:134,question:"Who was the last person Jesus appeared to after his resurrection according to Paul?",option:{a:"Mary Magdalene",b:"Joseph of Arimathea  ",c:"Paul",d:"Thomas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:135,question:"How many disciples of Jesus Christ were fishermen? ",option:{a:"two  ",b:"three  ",c:"four",d:"five"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:136,question:"Who among the seven deacons was an evangelist who had four daughters who prophesied?  ",option:{a:"Stephen",b:"Philip ",c:"Barnabas   ",d:"Nicholas"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:137,question:"“God has given your enemy into your hand this day, now, therefore, let me pin him to the earth with one stroke of the spear, and I will not strike him twice”. This statement was made to David by",option:{a:"Abishai ",b:"Abner    ",c:"Ahimelech ",d:"David’s armour bearer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:138,question:"The phrase ‘you cows of Bashan’ referred to ",option:{a:"Cows in the land of Bashan  ",b:"The fat and greedy men of Israel who oppress the priest ",c:"The fat and greedy women of Israel who oppress the poor  ",d:"The fat rich women of Samaria who oppress the poor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:139,question:"The book of _______ mostly emphasized social justice ",option:{a:"Amos ",b:"Ezekiel  ",c:"Hoshea  ",d:"Isaiah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:140,question:"Among the spiritual gifts, love is supreme because it ",option:{a:"facilitates development ",b:"gives room for friendship ",c:"has eternal value ",d:"promotes understanding"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:141,question:"John the Baptist describes Jesus to his two disciples as the ",option:{a:"beloved Son of God ",b:"great one of Israel ",c:"holy one of God",d:"lamb of God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:142,question:"Joseph’s brothers hated him the more because ",option:{a:"he dreamed about his future dominion over his family members ",b:"he used to give his father evil reports about them ",c:"his father had him at his old age ",d:"his father made a special robe for him"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:143,question:"After eating the forbidden fruit Adam’s and Eve’s eyes opened and they realized that they ",option:{a:"had sinned against God",b:"had disobeyed God   ",c:"were naked  ",d:"had been deceived by the serpent."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:144,question:"What did Ahab do to Prophet Micaiah for speaking the truth about the war between Israel and Syria? ",option:{a:"he promoted him ",b:"he gave him a gift ",c:"he denied him any fox ",d:"he imprisoned him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:145,question:"The Amalekites who opposed the Israelites in the wilderness were from the lineage of  ",option:{a:"Benjamin ",b:"Jacob ",c:"Esau ",d:"Reuben"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:146,question:"During the period of three and a half years of drought in Israel, the man who hid one hundred prophets of God in a cave was  ",option:{a:"Isaiah  ",b:"Lisha ",c:"Elijah ",d:"Obadiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:147,question:"During his first missionary journey, Paul first recorded sermon was delivered at  ",option:{a:"Perga   ",b:"Iconium ",c:"Antioch",d:"Lystra "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:297,question:"God blessed and hallowed the seventh day because",option:{a:"it was the day He rested from creation",b:"it was the day He created man",c:"He wanted it to be a day of worship",d:"He saw that all He had created was good."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:298,question:"Noah’s ark was sustained during the flood by its",option:{a:"resting on the highest mountains",b:"being rowed on the waters",c:"floating on the water",d:"being anchored safely"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:299,question:"God visited the children of Israel on Mount Sinai during the giving of  the commandments through",option:{a:"a storm",b:"mist and dew",c:"smoke and fire",d:"a still small voice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:300,question:"When asked to interpret Pharaoh’s dream, Joseph’s first response was",option:{a:"...God has revealed to Pharaoh what he is about to do.",b:"...It is not in me; God will give Pharaoh a favourable answer.",c:"...God will shortly bring it to pass.",d:"…let Pharaoh select a man discrete and wise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:301,question:"When Joshua fell upon his face during Israel’s defeat at Ai, God told him to rise and",option:{a:"send more courageous soldiers to Ai",b:"encourage the people",c:"pray fervently against their enemies",d:"sanctify the people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:302,question:"God guided Abraham’s steward in choosing a wife for Isaac by",option:{a:"teaching him how to select a good woman",b:"leading a lady to fulfil his prayer request",c:"taking him to Abraham’s fatherland",d:"giving him an exemplary woman."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:303,question:"Why was God angry with Eli?",option:{a:"Eli’s sons disregarded the people’s warning",b:"Eli’s sons were wicked people.",c:"Eli’s sons dishonoured God and he treated them with levity.",d:"Eli’s sons were appointed as priests against God’s will."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:304,question:"Laxity in disciplining children is dangerous to both the family and society as exemplified by",option:{a:"Jonathan",b:"Tamar",c:"Absalom",d:"Ahikam."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:305,question:"God promised Abraham that nations of the earth shall be blessed through him because",option:{a:"he had obeyed Him",b:"his descendants had obeyed Him",c:"of his kindness to Hagar",d:"of  his exemplary leadership."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:306,question:"The punishment for Adam and Eve’s sin was that they",option:{a:"were driven out of the garden",b:"would be naked forever",c:"would never fellowship with God",d:"would be enemies of crawling animals."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:307,question:"‘Do not destroy him; for who can stretch out his hand on the LORD’S anointed, and be guiltless?’ In the statement above, David was acknowledging God’s role in",option:{a:"Abishai’s command",b:"Saul’s leadership",c:"Samuel’s priesthood",d:"Elijah’s prophet hood."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:308,question:"Saul’s decision to consult a medium displayed his lack of",option:{a:"faith in his army",b:"faith in God",c:"leadership qualities",d:"respect for the dead."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:309,question:"Solomon made the most unwise decision by engaging in",option:{a:"marriages to foreign women",b:"alliances with his brothers",c:"so many wars of conquest",d:"developmental works."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:310,question:"The man of God whose word was ignored by Kings Ahab and Jehoshaphat was",option:{a:"Elijah",b:"Zedekiah",c:"Malakiah",d:"Micaiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:311,question:"Baal did not answer his worshippers at the contest on Mount Carmel because he",option:{a:"was annoyed with their sacrifice",b:"did not hear",c:"wanted to disgrace his worshippers",d:"was asleep."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:312,question:"The workmen who repaired the house of the LORD during Josiah’s religious reforms were not made to account for the money given them because they",option:{a:"did not receive the money directly",b:"lacked accounting capabilities",c:"bribed the Temple officials",d:"were honest workmen."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:313,question:"During Jehoiakim’s reign, Judah was destroyed as punishment for Manasseh’s sin of",option:{a:"keeping Temple prostitutes in the land",b:"defiling the vessels in the Temple",c:"offering unacceptable sacrifice",d:"shedding innocent blood."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:314,question:"Nehemiah responded to the opposition of the enemies of Israel by",option:{a:"telling the people not to say a word",b:"reporting the issue to King Artaxerxes",c:"inviting them to dialogue in the King’s court",d:"asking God to return their taunt back to them."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:315,question:"Nebuchadnezzar ordered his subjects to worship the image he set up whenever they",option:{a:"heard his voice",b:"saw him stand before the image",c:"heard the sound of the horn",d:"were told to do so."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:316,question:"‘What is this that you have done!”  The people in the ship asked Jonah the question above because",option:{a:"he was fast asleep in the ship",b:"they knew he was fleeing from the LORD",c:"he lied to them about his presence in the ship",d:"they realized that he had made attempts to commit suicide."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:317,question:"What shall I do with you, O Ephraim? What shall I do with you, O Judah? Your love is like a morning cloud...” In the statement above, the love of Israel is compared to a morning cloud because it",option:{a:"disappears fast",b:"withers",c:"is cloudy",d:"darkens the day"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:318,question:"According to Amos, God desires knowledge of Him rather than",option:{a:"fervent prayers",b:"dependency on the Law",c:"the multitude of prophecies",d:"burnt offerings"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:319,question:"In his vision, Isaiah’s guilt was taken away and his sin forgiven after",option:{a:"the angel of the LORD appeared to him",b:"his mouth was touched with a burning coal",c:"the seraphim had spoken to him",d:"he had agreed to serve God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:320,question:"The prophet who was ordained from the womb for God’s service was",option:{a:"Jeremiah",b:"Isaiah",c:"Ezekiel",d:"Hosea."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:321,question:"According to Jeremiah, the anger of God towards Israel would only be reduced by",option:{a:"His mercy",b:"the prophet’s repentance",c:"the prophet’s prayers",d:"His glory."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:322,question:"When Zechariah saw the angel of the Lord standing on the right side of the altar of incense, he",option:{a:"cried out to him",b:"was troubled and afraid",c:"rejoiced in the Lord",d:"left the Temple immediately."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:323,question:"‘Follow me and leave the dead to bury their own dead’ By this statement, Jesus means that",option:{a:"disciples shall not attend burials",b:"there is no life after death",c:"following Him comes before anything else",d:"shall leave their families in God’s care"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:324,question:"The disciples became terrified when they saw Jesus walking on the sea because",option:{a:"they thought He would drown",b:"they thought He was a ghost",c:"they lacked faith in Him",d:"there was a great storm."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:325,question:"The Jews sought to kill Jesus after He healed the man at the pool of Bethzatha because they thought that He",option:{a:"claimed to have authority to forgive sins",b:"made Himself equal with God",c:"did not agree with the law of Moses",d:"said that He was born before Abraham."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:326,question:"In the parable of the sower, the seed that fell among the thorns symbolized the one who hears the word but",option:{a:"does not understand it",b:"loses it to the enemy",c:"does not immediately receive it",d:"the cares of the world choke it."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:327,question:"Jesus encouraged His followers to rejoice when they were 	persecuted because",option:{a:"great would be their reward in heaven",b:"angels would come to their aid",c:"they would not lack anything good",d:"all their sins would be forgiven."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:328,question:"‘Blessed are you, Simon Bar-Jona ! For flesh and blood has not revealed this to you...’ As exemplified by the statement above, for believers to be able to identify with Jesus, they must",option:{a:"offer their lives",b:"be led by the Spirit",c:"keep all the commandments",d:"vow not to deny Him."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:329,question:"Jesus drove the money changers and sellers of doves out of the Temple because",option:{a:"the people defiled it with dubious business",b:"there was no need for animal sacrifice anymore",c:"the people were disobedient to the Law",d:"animals and birds were not allowed in it."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:330,question:"The tearing of the curtain of the Temple into two at the death of Jesus signifies",option:{a:"the passing away of the prophets",b:"direct access to God through Christ",c:"that Jesus was a powerful person",d:"that God was truly with Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:331,question:"“Tell people, His disciples came by night and stole him away while we were asleep...” The intention of the speaker in the statement above was to",option:{a:"implicate the disciples",b:"absolve the soldiers from all blame",c:"deny the resurrection story",d:"convince the authority"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:332,question:"Jesus charged His followers to walk in the light while they had the light so that they may",option:{a:"have eternal life",b:"become custodians of it",c:"have the light of life",d:"become sons of it."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:333,question:"In the early Church, believer devoted themselves to the",option:{a:"daily distribution of food",b:"apostles’ teaching and fellowship",c:"breaking of bread in the Temple",d:"performance of miracles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:334,question:"The disciple that went to preach in Samaria after the great persecution in Jerusalem was",option:{a:"Philip",b:"Andrew",c:"Peter",d:"James."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:335,question:"Saul was convened so that he might",option:{a:"cause confusion among the Jews",b:"help Peter in his work",c:"not be killed for his sins",d:"spread the word to the Gentiles."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:336,question:"What effect did the decision of the Council of Jerusalem have on the early Church?",option:{a:"Members became more untied",b:"the Church experienced freedom from persecution",c:"The Jews became leaders of the community.",d:"Gentiles were free to be members of the Church"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:337,question:"Paul in Romans stated that the righteousness of God has been manifested through",option:{a:"the Law",b:"the priests",c:"faith in Jesus",d:"Temple sacrifices."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:338,question:"According to Romans, all who were baptized into Christ were also baptized into His",option:{a:"crucifixion",b:"persecution",c:"suffering",d:"death"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:339,question:"According to Paul in Philippians, humility means giving consideration to other people’s",option:{a:"wealth",b:"weakness",c:"interests",d:"needs."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:340,question:"In Corinthians, believers are taught to forgive one another in order to",option:{a:"keep Satan from gaining advantage",b:"prevent the wrongdoer from losing his salvation",c:"remove the curse from the offender",d:"discourage the offender from committing more sin."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:341,question:"In Corinthians, Paul stated that by one Spirit we were",option:{a:"free from bondage of sin",b:"united into one church",c:"committee to Christian service",d:"baptized into one body"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:342,question:"Paul commended the churches in Macedonia for giving out of their freewill to the",option:{a:"saints",b:"poor",c:"priests",d:"sick."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:343,question:"‘Pay all of  them their dues, taxes to whom taxes are due, revenue to whom revenue is due, respect to whom respect is due, honour to whom honour is due’. Paul made the statement above to the Church at",option:{a:"Thessalonica",b:"Rome",c:"Corinth",d:"Ephesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:344,question:"At the second coming of Christ, those who are alive shall be",option:{a:"bound for life",b:"caught up together with the Lord",c:"separated from the dead",d:"taken to the new Jerusalem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:345,question:"According to James, treatment of brethren at fellowship should not be based on",option:{a:"appearance",b:"sentiments",c:"gender",d:"age."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:346,question:"Peter in his epistle, charged his fellow elders to",option:{a:"take care of their families",b:"be strong in their faith",c:"have compassion on the weak",d:"tend the flock of God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:646,question:"According to Joseph’s interpretation to Pharaoh’s dreams; the seven empty ears blighted by the east wind represented seven years of",option:{a:"famine.",b:"abundance.",c:"farming.",d:"Harvest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:647,question:"Moses was born at a period when the Hebrew were",option:{a:"suffering.",b:"increasing.",c:"backsliding.",d:"rejoicing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:648,question:"“…who is the Lord that I should heed his voice and let Israel go”? After this statement, Pharaoh",option:{a:"engaged Israel into forced labour with task masters.",b:"ordered midwives to kill all males born to Israelites.",c:"asked Israelites to fetch their own straws to produce bricks.",d:"decreed that Israelites’ male babies be drowned in the Nile."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:649,question:"The name Moses means",option:{a:"baptized in water",b:"abandoned in water.",c:"drawn out of water.",d:"thrown into water."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:650,question:"After the departure of the Israelites God made Pharaoh pursue them in order to",option:{a:"force Israel to return to Egypt.",b:"hasten Israel’s journey through the wilderness.",c:"make Israel obey Moses.",d:"get glory over Pharaoh and his host."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:651,question:"Who among the following kings was raised by God against the Israelites for going after the Canaanite gods?",option:{a:"Agap",b:"Jabin",c:"Zebah",d:"Zalmunnal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:652,question:"Deborah, a prophetess who was a judge in Israel was the wife of",option:{a:"Joshua.",b:"Abijah.",c:"Lappidoth.",d:"Sisera."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:653,question:"The sons of Eli were regarded as worthless men for all the following reasons except",option:{a:"sleeping with the women at the tent of meeting",b:"failing to attend the places of worship regularly.",c:"taking the meat for sacrifice before boiling.",d:"showing no respect for God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:654,question:"Who was the first king of Israel?",option:{a:"Kish",b:"David",c:"Solomon",d:"Saul"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:655,question:"Joel and Abijah were the sons of",option:{a:"Eli.",b:"Saul",c:"Samuel",d:"David."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:656,question:"“...Behold, to obey is better than sacrifice and to hearken than the fat of rams”. This statement was Samuel’s reaction to",option:{a:"David’s defense of his sin.",b:"Saul’s defense of disobedience.",c:"King Agag’s defense of his victory.",d:"Eli’s defense of the sins of his sons."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:657,question:"On Mount Gilboa, king Saul decided to commit suicide in order to avoid",option:{a:"ridicule from the Philistines.",b:"witnessing the death of his sons",c:"being killed by his armour-bearer.",d:"the agony of the injuries received."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:658,question:"David bitterly mourned when Abner was slain by",option:{a:"Ishbosheth.",b:"Absalom.",c:"Asahel.",d:"Joab."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:659,question:"One of the main features of Solomon’s prayer at the dedication of the Temple was the",option:{a:"celebration of God who is faithful to his covenant",b:"recognition that God loves sacrifices.",c:"assertion that God dwells in man-made houses.",d:"proclamation that no prayers be henceforth made outside the temple."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:660,question:"In spite of Solomon’s apostasy, his empire remained intact until his death because",option:{a:"God deferred, for David’s sake, the punishment due to him",b:"he won decisive victories over his enemies.",c:"he always took wise decisions",d:`. 
he made surrounding nations fight among themselves.`},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:661,question:"“Your father made our yoke heavy. Now therefore, lighten the hard service of your father.” These were the words of",option:{a:"Jeroboam",b:"Solomon",c:`.         
David`,d:"Ahijah."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:662,question:"Obadiah, Ahabs servant, made history for himself by",option:{a:"arresting the prophets of Yahweh",b:`. 
executing all the prophets.`,c:"hiding and feeding some of the prophets in a cave.",d:"D inciting the prophets to rebel against king Ahab."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:663,question:"The contest between Elijah and the prophets of Baal took place at mount",option:{a:"Olive.",b:"Tabor.",c:"Sinai",d:"Camel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:664,question:"King Jehoshaphat was commended for adopting his father’s policies which included",option:{a:"removing Maacah, his grandmother from being queen.",b:"waging wars with the king of Israel.",c:"allowing the cult prostitutes to operate.",d:"burning of incense at the high places."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:665,question:"God’s constant love for unfaithful Israel is demonstrated in the book of",option:{a:"Amos",b:"Isaiah",c:"Hosea",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:666,question:"During the rebuilding of the temple, Zerubbabel rejected the offer of help from the",option:{a:"inhabitants of Ammon.",b:"people of Samaria.",c:"friends of Sanballat and Tobiah",d:"governors of the provinces beyond the rivers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:667,question:"“And I asked them concerning the Jews that survived, who has escaped exile, and concerning Jerusalem...” These were the words of",option:{a:"Jeremiah.",b:"Nehemiah",c:"Ezra.",d:"Hanani."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:668,question:"The presentation of Myrrh to Jesus signifies Jesus’",option:{a:"humility and servant hood.",b:"suffering and impending death.",c:"lordship on earth.",d:"kingship and messiah ship."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:669,question:"“My son your sins are forgiven”. These were the words of Jesus to the",option:{a:"demoniac.",b:"paralytic.",c:"man born blind",d:"centurion’s servant."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:670,question:"Peter called for the construction of three booths for Jesus, Moses and Elijah, respectively during",option:{a:"the transfiguration.",b:"the Ascension.",c:"Jesus’ arrest.",d:"the Passover feast."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:671,question:"The incidents that took place following Jesus’ death on the cross did not include the",option:{a:"tearing into two of the temple’s veil.",b:"quaking of the earth that broke the rocks.",c:"the opening of the tombs.",d:"trembling of the chief priest and his conversion."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:672,question:"“How is it that you a Jew ask a drink of me...” This statement was made by the",option:{a:"Gentile woman.",b:"woman of Samaria.",c:"possessed woman.",d:"woman of Galilee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:673,question:"The Jews showed their hatred for Paul and Barnabas in Pisidia by",option:{a:"dragging out the apostles for stoning.",b:"insisting and driving them out of the Synagogue.",c:"influencing leading men in the city to drive them out.",d:"beating and stoning them in the Synagogue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:674,question:"When Jesus said “apart from me you can do nothing”, he 	meant that Christians",option:{a:"pray without ceasing",b:`. 
must faithfully trust in Him always.`,c:"cannot pass examinations if they did not pray.",d:"should expect God to do everything for them."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:675,question:"On the day of Ascension, Jesus promised his disciples",option:{a:"peace in the kingdom of God.",b:"amazing grace.",c:"power of  the Holy Ghost.",d:"His abiding physical presence."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:676,question:"On Ascension Day two men in white robes inform the disciples that Jesus would",option:{a:"send for them.",b:"be seen in heaven.",c:"prepare a place for them.",d:"come again."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:677,question:"“Go up and join this chariot”.  This statement was made to",option:{a:"John.",b:"Paul.",c:"James.",d:"Philip."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:678,question:"Saul was converted on his journey to",option:{a:"Samaria",b:"Jerusalem.",c:"Salamis.",d:"Damascus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:679,question:"Which of the following places was not visited by Paul during his first missionary journey?",option:{a:"Salamis",b:"Athens",c:"Antioch of Syria",d:"Antioch of Pisidia"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:680,question:"Paul was stoned and dragged out of the city by",option:{a:"the Lyconians and the Ephesians.",b:"enemies of the healed lame man",c:`. 
Jews from Antioch and Iconium.`,d:"Jews in the Synagogue."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:681,question:"The resurrection of Jesus is significant to Christians for it 	marked the",option:{a:"end of the Jewish faith.",b:"assurance of eternal life for Christians.",c:"beginning of Christianity",d:"end of Jesus’ earthly ministry."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:682,question:"According to Paul, ‘As sin reigned in death, grace also might reign through righteousness to",option:{a:"faith in God’.",b:"the knowledge of God’.",c:"eternal life",d:"the glory of the father’."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:683,question:"Paul in Romans declared “for as by one man’s disobedience many were made sinners, so by one man’s obedience many will be made...”",option:{a:"innocent.",b:"righteous.",c:"faithful.",d:"Christians."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:684,question:"Which of the following is not true about spiritual gifts as taught by Paul?",option:{a:"Gifts should be used with all modesty",b:"No gift can be independent of others",c:"Gifts have nothing to do with the level of one’s faith",d:"Specific gifts perform specific functions"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:685,question:"In his comparison of the human body with the body of Christ, Paul did not mention the",option:{a:"hand.",b:"foot.",c:"eye.",d:"nose."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:686,question:"The New Life in Christ operates through",option:{a:"humility.",b:"the name of Jesus.",c:"one body.",d:"wisdom."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:687,question:"‘Death is swallowed up in victory, “oh death, where is your victory”? This statement is found in the book of",option:{a:"Corinthians.",b:"Romans.",c:"Galatians.",d:"Philemon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:688,question:"According to Paul in Corinthians the gospel message could only be lifeless when Christians",option:{a:"deny the resurrection message.",b:"persecute one another.",c:"gossip among themselves.",d:"entertain idolatrous practices."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:689,question:"Paul asked the Thessalonians to imitate his action of",option:{a:"demanding support from his converts.",b:"performing miracles",c:"healing the sick.",d:"working for his personal upkeep."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:690,question:"With respect to the date of the Parosia, Paul advised Thessalonians to",option:{a:"be sober in maintaining their hope of salvation.",b:"disregard all speculations about it.",c:"know that the day would be announced later.",d:"enjoy peace and security in the face of danger."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"}],i={subject:e,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,i as default,o as status,e as subject,t as total};
